# 哈喽 大家好
Hello, everybody.
# 我是王刚
I'm Wang Gang.
# 这两个是我的徒弟
These two are my apprentices.
# 这个徒弟姓王
This one's last name is Wang.
# 就是在前两天拍的那个视频里面
He was in the video that was shot a couple of days ago.
# 大家说长得跟我很像
People said he looks like me.
# 其实我们之前并不认识
We actually didn't know each other before.
# 你是怎么来的
How did you get here?
# 介绍一下
Please introduce yourself.
# 大家好 我是王介平
Hello, I'm Wang Jieping
# 我是泸州人
I'm from Luzhou.
# 是通过发私信过来的
It was by private message.
# 对吧
Right?
# 是 我也是通过
Yeah.
# 万千中的简历里面选出来的 也是一种缘分
It's a kind of destiny to be chosen out of thousands of resumes.
# 就是过来学习手艺的
I'm here to learn to cook.
# 这里有一个就是我们
There was one of the comments,
# 评论下面就是前几天教做那个麻婆豆腐
The comment below the previous video about how to make Mapo Tofu.
# 跟徒弟交流的一个视频下面写着
Below that video of communication with an apprentice, it says
# 有一个评论说
One comment said
# 醉翁之意不在酒
he has bad intentions other than learning cooking skills,
# 都想当网红
They all want to be Internet celebrities.
# 你过来是想干什么的
What did you come here to do?
# 你讲一下你心里话
Tell me what's on your mind.
# 其实我
Actually, I...
# 真的是过来学手艺（厨艺）的
I'm really here to learn cooking skills.
# 我对这个（自媒体）行业其实并不是太清楚
I don't really know too much about this (content creator) industry
# 不是说为了做网红过来的
He didn't came here to be famous on the Internet.
# 为了学手艺过来的
He came here to learn skills.
# 所以关于这个以后就大家不要说了啊
So please don't make false accusations anymore.
# 漆二娃呢
How about Qi Erwa?
# 也是学手艺吧
You're also here to learn skills.
# 学手艺
learn cooking skills
# 嗯 还有一个女徒弟
Yes, there' s a female apprentice.
# （评论）就是说这个男徒弟应该是我亲戚
Another comment said that this male apprentice should be a relative of mine.
# 我再说一下
I'll say it again.
# 我们没有任何亲戚关系
We're not related to each other in any way.
# 我们只是师徒关系
We're just master and apprentice.
# 没有任何亲戚关系
No relatives whatsoever.
# 虽然都姓王
Even though we both named Wang.
# 虽然长得有点像
We look a little alike, though.
# 还有一个就是问我们还收徒弟吗
The other thing is to ask if I still take apprentices.
# 这个学费多少
How much is this tuition?
# 其实这个怎么讲呢
Actually, how do I put this?
# 过来学东西是我挑他们不是他(们)挑我
I pick them, not they pick me.
# 如果是他挑我的话
If he had picked me.
# 那么可能我们会讲一个
Then maybe we'll talk about.
# 收学费多少钱怎么样
How much is the tuition fee?
# 但是我挑他
But I picked him.
# 我既然挑中了他
I've picked him.
# 就会把我会的都交给他们
I'll teach them everything I know.
# 不收费
free of charge
# 反而还有一些工资拿
They even get paid.
# 这种事情上哪里去找 好好学真的
Where do you find such things?
# 我们那个标题嘛没有最好吃的菜
Our title wrote there is no such thing as the best food.
# 只有更会做菜的人什么逻辑
only man who can cook better? What do you think that means?
# 你懂这个是什么逻辑吗
Do you understand the meaning of this?
# 啊 你还是不懂
Ah, you still don't get it.
# 没有最好吃的菜只有最会做菜的人
There's no such thing as the best food, only the best cooks.
# 这句话我的意思是
That's what I mean by that.
# 就是把手艺学精了
It's about as long as you're better at your skills,
# 做出来的菜只有更好吃的
the food only gets better.
# 没有最好吃的是这个意思
That's what it means to not have the best food.
# 然后我看一下
Let me take a look.
# 还有网友还有一个问题
There's one more question from the Internet.
# 还有就是感觉王刚现在没有东西做了
It also feels like Wang Gang has nothing more to do now.
# 是不是江郎才尽了
Is he running out of ideas?
# 这个我不知道你是从哪里看出
I don't know where you got that...
# 我是江郎才尽了啊
...that I'm "running out of my talent".
# 其实我会的东西挺多的
I actually know much more.
# 只是怎么说呢
Just how do I put it?
# 现在要一步一步的把它做出来
I need to shot the videos step by step.
# 包括你们看我做的那个什么
Including that you saw me do in previous videos,
# 糖色呀还有一些卤味料啊
Caramelized sugar colour and master stock.
# 还有一些香料之类的
And facts about spices.
# 这些东西
These things.
# 之前很少有拍到过
No one had ever made such videos before
# 当然后面的话会拍的越来越多
Of course, I will make more and more of that kind later.
# 还有就是怎么说呢
And how do I put it?
# 人在不断的学习的话
If people are constantly learning
# 他就没有一个瓶颈
their skills would never hit a plateau
# 不会讲什么江郎才尽啊
So there is no such thing as out of talent.
# 就算我江郎才尽了
Let's say I'm out of talent in the end.
# 那我的徒弟们的话
What about my apprentices?
# 他们也会继续去深挖一些东西去学习
And they're going to continue to dig deeper to learn.
# 去学习更多的东西
To learn more.
# 怎么会讲江郎才尽呢
Why would somebody say out of talent?
# 我觉得这个词用在我们身上都不适合
I don't think that's the right word for any of us.
# 我比他们都大好几岁
I'm a few years older than all of them.
# 可能比漆二娃要大十几岁是吧
I am probably more than a decade older than Qi Erwa, right?
# 11岁
11 years
# 我比你大十几岁
I'm more than a decade older than you.
# 我比你大几岁 大6岁对吧
I'm a few years older than you are. Six years older, right?
# 我这比他年长的这几年
The years I have been older than them.
# 我学了很多东西
I learned a lot.
# 现在
now
# 我除了做视频的情况下
Except in the case of shooting videos.
# 我平时还要抽时间来带他们
I still have time to teach them.
# 就是上次拍那个麻婆豆腐嘛
The last time we made Mapo Tofu.
# 嗯 其实就是一个纯记录
Well, it's really just a record.
# 大家说四川话听不懂
You guys said couldn't understand Sichuanese.
# 现在后面改的话说普通话
Now I'm changing the language back to Mandarin.
# 你们想想还有什么没有
Can you think of anything else?
# 那你过来学厨艺
So you came here to learn to cook?
# 你的目标是什么
What's your goal?
# 你的理想是什么
What's your vision?
# 我的想法就是
My thought is...
# 在王刚老师这里学好了以后 然后自己回去
When I finish my apprenticeship with Master Wang Gang, I'll go back on my home town.
# 嗯 开个店
Open a restaurant.
# 开个小店 对吧 对
Open a small restaurant, right? - Yeah.
# 对 就是很简单
Yes, it's very simple.
# 养家糊口 跟我以前的想法是一模一样的
To provide for family. That's exactly what I had in mind when I was young.
# 我曾经也是这种想法
That's what I thought before.
# 现在当然有了这个
Now of course we have this.
# 媒体时代嘛 然后把这些
The media age. And then...
# 教更多人做家常菜 对吧
Teach more people how to cook at home, right?
# 漆二娃她以前学厨艺
Previously when Qi Erwa learned to cook.
# 态度她不是特别的好
She doesn't have a particularly good attitude.
# 就是一般般
Just so-so.
# 现在来了一个肯学的人过来
And now here comes another apprentice.
# 他们之间肯定是会有压力的
There's definitely pressure between them.
# 她有压力她才有动力
She's motivated by pressure.
# 如果你学不好的话
If you can't learn.
# 你不想学
You don't want to learn.
# 有人会去学
Someone is going to learn.
# 对吧
right?
# 有竞争才有压力嘛
There's pressure when there's competition.
# 然后
And...
# 漆二娃有没有什么想说的
Is there anything else you'd like to say?
# 我以前没有学好的东西
I hadn't learned well before.
# 我现在会努力的把它学好
I'll try to learn how to cook better now.
# 嗯 大家看着吧
Yeah, you'll see.
# 嗯嗯
Mm-hmm.
# 大家一起来见证他们两个人的成长
We're all here to witness the growth of the two of them.
# 今天就到这里 聊到这里
That's all for today.
# 拜拜
Bye-bye